《超感警探》前情提要
Previously on "The Mentalist"...
她说血腥约翰左肩膀有个纹身
She told me Red John has a tattoo on his left shoulder--
三个点
three dots.
这是我的筹码
That's my leverage.
把五名疑犯同时
Gather all five suspects together
集合到一个地方
at the same place, same time,
然后再检查是否有纹身
and then start checking for the tattoo.
如何才能做到呢
How do we do that?
-周四晚上八点见面  -好吧
- Meet me at 8:00 on Thursday night. - Fine.
周四晚上八点
Thursday night at 8:00.
-我需要你的帮助  -没问题
- I'll need your help. - Well, then you've got it.
你如果不去  他就会认为你是血腥约翰
If you don't show up, he will assume you're Red John.
我如果去了  你和简
If I do this, will you and Jane drop
就不会再怀疑我是血腥约翰了吗
the whole that "I'm Red John" business?
以后绝对不会了
For once and for all.
你真的确定了吗
You really think you've got him?
-是的  -此案结束的时候我要在场
- I do. - I want to be there when you end this.
就等您这句话呢
I was hoping you'd say that.
血腥约翰
Red John.
今晚我若能去见你
Nothing would give me more pleasure
那是再高兴不过了
than to be with you there tonight.
血腥约翰  有个纹身
Red john... has a tattoo.
左臂上有三个点  就在肩膀上
Three dots on his left arm. On the shoulder.
你们都得
And you all...
给我看
are gonna show me...
立刻动手
Now.
开始脱吧  快
Let's go. Come on.
对了  脱掉
That's it. Take it off.
太荒唐了
Nonsense.
很好
Very good.
不是你想的那样
It's not what you think.
你弄错了
You got it wrong.
我不是血腥约翰
I'm not Red John.
派翠克  等等  派翠克
Patrick, wait. Patrick!
看  这边
Look... here.
看
Look.
站起来
On your feet.
到他们俩那边去
Over with those two.
你们别动
You stay there.
好了  你们三个
Okay, you three...
到墙边站着  快
Over against that wall-- now.
等等  不要
Wait! No!
快叫消防部门和急救人员过来
Call the fire department and E.M.Ts.
告诉他们这里有多人伤亡
Let them know that there's multiple casualties,
警戒线拉起来
and set up a perimeter.
是的  长官
Yes, ma'am.
-把你的手电筒给我  我进去  -给你
- Give me your flashlight. I-I'm going in. - Here you go.
简
Jane.
Jane?
史密斯探员
Agent Smith.
史密斯探员  我是特蕾莎·里斯本
Agent Smith, it's Teresa Lisbon.
-你没事吧  -发生了什么事
- Are you okay? - What happened?
这里刚刚发生了爆炸  急救人员已经在路上了
There was an explosion. The E.M.Ts are on their way.
他们会救治你
They're gonna help you.
-不许动  -什么
- Don't move! - What?
把手举起来
Put your hands in the air,
不然我就开枪了  快
or I'll shoot! Do it!
听着  我不明白你在说什么
Okay, listen, I don't know what you're talking about.
你明显搞错了
You're clearly making a big mistake.
史密斯往哪边走了
Which way did Smith go?
我的天哪  里斯本
Oh, my god, Lisbon.
头儿  我们必须得找到史密斯  他是血腥约翰
Boss? We have to find Smith. He's Red John.
我去找人帮忙
I'll get help.
简
Jane?
你能听到我讲话吗
Can you hear me?
简  快醒醒
Jane? Come on.
■
翻译：灰灰是菇凉  面条打包子  Michael  非燕  王小麦  那时花开
翻译：静静的木头  莎友友  壹不贰   时间轴：Sagelibra  Sweet宝宝
超感警探
第六季
第七集
■
校对&后期：灰灰是菇凉   精校&总监：灰灰是菇凉
你还好吧
You okay?
还好
I'm fine.
医生说简的情况稳定
The doctors say Jane's stable.
没受什么重伤
There's no major trauma or anything.
他只是醒不过来
He's just not awake.
现场发现了三个人的残骸
They found the remains of three people.
化验确认是布莱特·斯特尔斯  雷·哈弗内
Positive I.Ds for Bret Stiles, Ray Haffner,
和托马斯·麦卡利斯特的
and Thomas McAllister.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
我以为核攻击都干不掉布莱特·斯特尔斯呢
I would think Bret Stiles would survive a nuclear attack.
尸体都被烧焦了
The bodies are all burnt to a crisp,
但鉴证科还是提取出了DNA
but the crime techs did spot D.N.A. tests.
验尸官那边将结果与医疗记录进行比对
Coroner's office checked it against medical records.
已确认三位死者正是
Stiles, Haffner, and McAllister
斯特尔斯  哈弗内和麦卡利斯特
are all positively dead.
那史密斯呢  有人看到他吗
Uh, what about Smith? Any sightings?
还没  瑞斯比和范佩尔正在查
Not yet. Rigsby and Van Pelt are on it.
长官
Sir?
就知道在这儿能找到你
Ah, thought I might find you here.
你没事吧
Are you all right?
没事  不过我确实得喝杯咖啡
Uh, I'm fine. I could use a cup of coffee, actually.
你能帮我去买一杯吗
Would you go and get me one?
我们马上要开始联合追捕史密斯了
We're just about to coordinate the manhunt for Smith.
那你该赶快去抓他
Well, you should just go and get him.
我更想待在这里  长官
Well, I'd like to stay here, sir.
-你是...  -周和其他组员应付得来
- Well, are... - Cho and the team... they can handle it.
你是要拒绝执行我的命令吗
Are you refusing a direct order?
不是的
Well, no.
我只是想在这里陪他
No, I just want to stay here with him.
你给我听清楚了
Wh-why don't you listen a little more closely?
我命令你现在马上离开
I am ordering you to get out there,
带领你的组员一起去抓捕史密斯
put your team together, and get Smith.
简  简  那个呼叫按钮在哪呢
Jane? Jane? Where's the damn call button?
我去叫护士
I'll--I'll get the nurse.
简
Jane.
头儿
Hey, boss.
我们现在认为  是血腥约翰带去的炸弹
Our working theory is that Red John brought in the bomb
想要杀死简和其他嫌犯
to kill Jane and the other suspects.
好吧  但怎么布下的
Okay, but how?
可能是血腥约翰随身偷偷带进去的
Chances are, Red John snuck the bomb in on his person.
犯罪现场小组从墙上发现了
Crime techs have pulled fragments of the bomb casings
炸弹外壳的碎片  碎片非常小
from the walls-- very small fragments.
这说明火药密度高  威力很大
This tells us that the explosive was dense, high-powered.
那肯定不是自制的
That doesn't sound homemade.
没错  我猜是军用级别的
No. Military grade's my bet,
这就说明我们能够追踪到来源
which means it could be traceable.
这些是最有可能的来源
These are the most likely sources.
查查看最近他们中
Check for any recent thefts
有谁曾报告丢失过炸药
of missing explosives from any of them.
好的  马上去
All right, will do.
-有线索了吗  -是的
- Got something? - Yeah.
里斯本在史密斯逃走前曾击中过他
Lisbon wounded Smith before he escaped.
他是带着枪伤在四处逃窜
He's walking around with a bullet.
医院看到枪伤必须向警方报备
Well, hospitals have to declare gunshot wounds,
所以他不能去看急诊
so he can't go to an E.R.
没错  他需要一个不会声张的医生
Right, so he needs a doctor who'll keep quiet.
史密斯一直在萨克拉门托工作
Smith's based here in Sacramento,
我查了一下全市他负责过的案件
so I looked into some of his old cases around town.
他所在的缉毒小组
He was part of a task force
去年在萨克拉门托市南部
that arrested Dr. Alek Lavrov
抓捕过阿列克·拉夫罗夫医生
last year in south Sac.
一个非法开具奥施康定[强力止痛药]处方的医生
A Dr. Feelgood writing illegal oxycontin scripts.
Dr. Feelgood指的是常给病人开出兴奋剂等安慰性药方的医生
-然后呢  -案子审判不顺利
- So? - So the case went bad,
证物丢失  拉夫罗夫被无罪释放
evidence was lost, and Lavrov walked.
所以史密斯很清楚在哪能找到一位
So Smith knows exactly where to find a doctor
不会报警的医生
who won't talk to the cops.
很好  我们马上去查
Great, let's go check it out.
不是你想的那样
It's not what you think.
我不是血腥约翰
I'm not Red John.
派翠克  等等  看
Patrick, wait. Look.
欢迎回来
Welcome back.
里斯本
Lisbon.
你家里发生了爆炸
There was an explosion at your house.
我昏迷多久了
How long have I been out?
十二个小时
12 hours.
里德·史密斯是血腥约翰
Reede Smith is Red John.
我看到他肩膀上的纹身了
I saw the tattoo on his shoulder.
不只他有
He's not the only one.
麦卡利斯特身上也有
McAllister has one, too.
他已经死了  斯特尔斯和哈弗内也死了
He's dead. So are Stiles and Haffner.
-还有伯特仑  -伯特仑
- And Bertram. - Bertram?
他也有那个纹身
He has the tattoo as well.
我的天
Oh, my God.
他刚才还在这
He was just here.
他刚才就站在你身边
He was standing over you.
他  他还一直想让我离开
He--he was trying to get me to leave.
他是要杀了你
He was gonna kill you.
-我的衣服呢  -别着急  好吗
- Where are my clothes? - Slow down, okay?
我没事  我们没有时间了
No, it's okay. We don't have time.
简  简
Jane. Jane.
我的衣服呢
Where are my clothes?
我是特蕾莎·里斯本
This is Teresa Lisbon.
在全州境内发出里德·史密斯
Put out a statewide alert for the apprehension
和盖尔·伯特仑的通缉令
of Reede Smith and Gail Bertram.
没错  就是伯特仑局长
Yes, Director Bertram.
接近时务必小心
Approach with caution.
他们持有武器  十分危险
They're considered armed and dangerous.
他们其中一个就是血腥约翰
One of them is Red John.
伊凡·拉夫罗夫医生诊所
今日停业
请赶快离开  女士  警察办案
Move along, ma'am. Police business.
天啊
Ah, my God!
是的
Yes.
子弹还在你体内
The bullet is still inside you.
别废话了  赶紧取出来
No crap! Get it out!
会很疼的
This is going to hurt.
你确定不吃点止疼药
Are you sure you won't take something for the pain?
不吃
No...
不吃  我要保持警觉
No. I gotta stay sharp.
那就随你吧
As you like.
天啊
God!
老虎  老虎
Tiger, tiger.
史密斯在这
Smith in there?
是的  他快喊破喉咙了
Yeah. He's screaming his head off.
他不会成为麻烦的  你打算怎么做
He won't be a problem. How you wanna do it?
我刚从加调局得到消息
I just got word from inside CBI.
有几个探员正要来这里找史密斯
Couple of agents are coming here right now looking for Smith.
-那我们该怎么办  -赶紧了事
- So what do we do? - We hurry.
你进去搞定他  加调局的人来了我拖住他们
You go get him. I'll run interference if CBI shows.
好的
You got it.
从后面把他带出去  在那干掉他
Take him out the back. Do it there.
-他逼我这么做的  我是无辜的  -闭嘴
- He made me do this. I'm innocent. - Shut up.
只要他一走我就会报警的
I would have called the police as soon as he left.
-我不想惹麻烦  -闭嘴
- I don't want any trouble! - Quiet!
你也是组织的人
You association?
老虎  老虎  你为什么不给我们打电话
Tiger, tiger. Why didn't you call us?
说来真怪  因为我不相信你们
Funnily enough, I got trust issues.
你要信任你的朋友
Hey, you gotta trust your friends.
我是来帮你的  你能走路吗
I'm here to help you. Can you walk?
我得给他缝好  不然会失血的
I need to sew him up. He'll bleed.
我能走路
Ah... I can walk.
你是科德罗警探  对吧
Detective Cordero, right?
瑞斯比探员
Agent Rigsby.
你好
How are ya?
他是萨城警局的  负责柯克兰枪击案
He's, uh, Sac P.D. worked the Kirkland shooting.
这位是格蕾斯·范佩尔探员
This is Agent Grace Van Pelt.
你们怎么来萨城南部了
What brings you to South Sac?
我们跟一条线索过来抓里德·史密斯
We're chasing up a lead on Reede-- Reede Smith.
也就是  血腥约翰
AKA, Red John.
看来我们快你们一步
Looks like we beat you to the punch.
我的人已经进去抓他了
One of my guys is in there getting him right now.
需要我们看住后面吗
You want us to cover the back?
-不用  我们能搞定  -你确定
- No. No, we got it. - You sure?
虽然我们不是加调局的  但是我们也是警察
Hey, we might not be CBI, but we know what we're doing.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
什么事
Yep?
瑞斯比  你在哪里
Rigsby, where are you?
在医生办公室外面  史密斯好像在里面
Outside the doctor's office. Looks like Smith's inside.
有警察在你身边吗
Are there policemen with you?
有  怎么了
Yeah. Why?
好的  你仔细听清楚
Okay, listen carefully.
不要相信任何一名执法人员
Do not trust anyone in law enforcement.
谁也不能相信  明白吗
Anyone at all. Do you understand?
好的
You got it.
谢了
Thanks.
我们去后面四周看看
Let's, uh, go take a look around back.
等等
Wait a minute.
你们去哪里
Where are you going?
车就在这边
Car's back this way.
一切都安排好了
Everything's taken care of.
在附近有个安全屋  干净衣服  一名医生
We got a safe house nearby, fresh clothes, a doctor...
出城的路线也准备好了
A trip out of town.
安全屋
A safe house, huh?
我也对某个人说过一次
You know, I said that to someone once.
是吗  后来呢
Yeah? What happened after that?
我朝他后背开了六枪
I shot him six times in the back.
乖乖就范吧
Come on.
该死
Damn it.
放下武器
Drop your weapon!
站住
Stop!
-你没事吧  -没事  你还好吧
- You all right? - Yeah! You good?
嗯
Yeah.
史密斯趁乱逃走了
Smith got away during the fight.
那个警探也是
So did the detective.
头儿  他们想杀史密斯和我们  这是为什么
Boss, they were trying to kill Smith and us. Why?
-我不知道  -看看他的肩膀
- I don't know. - Check the shoulder.
-什么  -让他看看左肩
- What? - Ask him to check the left shoulder.
让瑞斯比把他衬衣脱了看他的肩膀
Have Rigsby take his shirt off and look at his shoulder.
里斯本想让你看他的左肩
Lisbon wants you to check his left shoulder.
怎么回事
What the hell?
有  他肩上有那个纹身
He's got it. He's got the tattoo.
头儿  这是怎么了
Boss, what's happening?
好  把他带回局里
All right, bring him in
别让任何人接近他
and don't let anybody else get to him.
带回去
Bring him in.
查到袭击你们的警察身份了吗
What do we know about the cop who attacked you?
这是我们抓到的那个  保罗·魏海根警官
This is the one we caught. Officer Paul Wiehagen.
当警察六年  模范警察
Six years on the force. Exemplary record,
受过几次表彰  没纪律问题
a couple of commendations, no real discipline problems.
那另一个  科德罗警探呢
What about the other one-- Detective Cordero?
打电话问了他队长
Put a call in to his captain.
说他一小时前请了病假
Said he called in sick an hour ago.
还是没查到伯特仑的行踪
And still no sign of Bertram.
那就着重调查我们抓到的这个
Let's focus on the one we do have.
或许简会弄清真相
Maybe Jane will figure it out.
有人派你杀里德·史密斯吗
Did someone send you to kill Reede Smith?
无可奉告
I got nothing to say.
你为什么要杀他
Why were you gonna murder him?
那纹身是怎么回事  有什么意义
What about the tattoo? What's it mean?
你不善言辞  我懂
You're not a big talker. I get it.
祸从口出嘛
Loose lips sink ships and all that.
坏消息是  你的表情控制得不够好
The bad news is, you have a lousy poker face.
所以我们要玩个你演我猜的小游戏
So we're gonna play a little game of show-and-tell.
我告诉你些事
I'm gonna tell you something,
你用表情告诉我
and you're gonna show me with your face
是对是错
whether I'm right or not.
有意思吗
That sound fun?
你偷过东西吗
You ever steal anything?
你背着女友偷腥过吗
Did you ever cheat on your girlfriend?
打过她吗
Hit her?
你喜欢施暴吗
Do you like causing pain?
我从没打过女人
I never hit a woman in my life.
你是一个由警察和其他政府官员
Do you belong to a secret organization of cops
组成的秘密组织成员吗
and other government officials?
是的
Yes.
你为维护那个组织的利益犯过罪
You've committed crimes on behalf of that organization before.
对吗
Right?
史密斯探员也是组织成员
Agent Smith is a member also...
对吗
Right?
组织派你去那个诊所杀他
The organization sent you to the doctor's office to kill him,
对吗
right?
加调局局长盖尔·伯特仑也是组织成员
CBI director Gail Bertram is also a member.
你不知道
You don't know.
等级太低了对吧
Too low on the totem pole, huh?
里德·史密斯探员是血腥约翰
Agent Reede Smith is Red John.
不知道
Don't know.
盖尔·伯特仑是血腥约翰
Gail Bertram's Red John.
不知道
Don't know.
你肩上的纹身是组织成员的标志
That tattoo on your shoulder is the membership sign.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
又对了
Right again.
还有个暗号
There's a password, too--
是你们成员间用来识别身份
Something you say as a greeting or a...
和求救的
distress signal.
"老虎  老虎"
"Tiger, tiger."
从我脑子里滚出去
Get out of my head.
一个腐败警察的秘密组织
A secret society of dirty cops.
血腥约翰是成员之一
And Red John's a member.
帕特里奇
Partridge.
他死之前对我说了"老虎  老虎"
He said "tiger, tiger" to me right before he died.
对  没错
Hmm. Yes. Yes.
他在求救
He was asking for help
寄希望于你也是成员之一
in the hopes that you were a member.
但是如果他也有纹身
But if he had a tattoo,
验尸报告里应该有
it would have been in the autopsy report.
不能相信什么报告
Well, you can't trust a file.
要亲眼看到才行
We have to see it.
我会让周去检查尸体
I'll have Cho track down the body.
但是很有可能帕特里奇已经下葬了
But Partridge could be buried by now.
那就让周带上铲子
Well, have Cho bring a shovel.
我们的人在找史密斯  伯特仑在外逃中
The team's looking for Smith, Bertram's on the run.
到底谁是血腥约翰
So who's Red John?
是伯特仑还是史密斯
Is it Bertram or Smith?
我要看着他们的眼睛才能确定
I need to look them both in the eye.
验尸官两天前把尸体送过来的
Yeah, the coroner released his body, like, two days ago.
-谋杀案被害人是吧  -是的
- Murder victim, huh? - Yeah.
我猜就是  所以才会一直留着他
I figured. That's why we held him for so long.
幸好你今天来了
Good thing you got here today.
明天就什么都看不到了
Tomorrow there won't be much left of him to look at.
在这儿
Here we go.
布雷特·帕特里奇
Brett Partridge.
帮把手
Give me a hand, huh?
你的了
He's all yours.
把刀给我
Give me your knife.
烧之前都会给他们穿上好衣服
They dress 'em before we burn 'em.
我也不知道为什么
Don't ask me why.
周发了张照片过来
Cho sent a picture.
说明什么
What does it mean?
你觉得这说明什么
What do you think it means?
史密斯处理好了么
What happened with Smith?
我们差点就在诊所那里解决他了
We almost got him at his doctor's office.
加调局的人来了
That CBI team showed up.
史密斯跑了
Smith's in the wind.
他可真会跑
That's a good place to be.
我有点事要处理
I've got some business in here,
在这儿等我
so wait for me.
谢谢  托马斯先生
Thank you, Mr. Thomas.
您很久没来了
We haven't seen you for a while.
很高兴见到你
Yeah. It's nice to see you.
史密斯现在可能在任何地方
Smith could be anywhere by now.
我试着追踪他手机上全球定位信号
I tried to trace the G.P.S. signal on his cell phone.
已经关闭好几个小时了
It's been dead for hours.
像他这样的腐败联调局警察一定会有一次性手机
A dirty F.B.I. cop like him has to have a burner.
拉夫罗夫医生说他还没缝合史密斯的伤口
Dr. Lavrov says he didn't get the chance to sew Smith up.
他现在还带着枪伤四处走动
He's still walking around with a bullet wound.
那么不管他在哪儿  情况一定不好
So he's in a bad way wherever he is.
最终一定会被人发现的
He'll get picked up by someone eventually.
是啊  但是发现他的警察
Yeah, but any cop who finds him...
太可怕了  我们谁都不能信
This is scary. We can't trust anyone.
是啊
Nope.
范佩尔探员
Agent Van Pelt.
你得帮帮我
You gotta help me.
史密斯探员
Agent Smith.
他们会杀了我的
They're gonna kill me.
我要自首
I wanna surrender.
你在哪儿
Where are you?
第十八大道
在市中心  给周打电话  他应该在附近
Downtown. Call Cho. He should be close.
知道了  我们这就来
Okay, we're on our way.
史密斯联系加调局了
Smith reached out to CBI.
他用了组织给他的一次性手机
He used the burner the association gave him.
我们监听了那部手机
We were listening.
他要自首
He's turning himself in.
没错  叛徒
Yeah. Rat.
加调局的人去接他了
That CBI team is on its way to get him now.
这可不行  他在哪儿
Well, we can't have that. Where is he?
离这儿不远的小巷子里  我们运气很不错
He's in an alley not too far from here. Our good luck.
他认识你吗
Does he know who you are?
不认识  在诊所那儿他没看见我
Nah, he didn't see me at the doctor's office.
好  你现在就是加调局探员了
All right. You are now a CBI agent.
要一起去吗  说不定挺好玩儿的
You want to come along? Could be fun.
不去了  我还有别的事要处理
No. I have some other business to take care of.
-到时再碰头吧  -行
- We'll meet up later. - You got it.
这次别失手了  行吗
Can you get it right this time?
是  长官
Yes, sir!
里德·史密斯探员
Agent Reede Smith?
在吗  范佩尔探员派我来的
You out there? Agent Van Pelt sent me.
你是谁
Who are you?
奥斯卡·科德罗探员  加调局的
Agent Oscar Cordero, CBI.
我来接你回去
I'm here to take you in.
你得保证我安全
You gotta keep me safe.
他们无处不在
They're everywhere.
没错
Yeah.
我们无处不在
We are.
天呐
God...
到车尾去
Back of the car now.
你不会真以为你能逃脱得了吧
You didn't really think you could get away from us, did you?
你懂事的  帮个忙  自己爬后备箱里去吧
You're a big boy. Do me a favor and get in the trunk yourself.
再让我歇会儿  行吗
Just give me a second, will you?
到后备箱里去歇吧
You'll have a second in the trunk.
别逼我动手
Now don't make me do painful things to you.
上车
Get in the car!
我有个条件  我要求完全豁免权
I'm gonna need a deal. Full immunity.
除非你们放过我  否则我一个字都不会说的
I'm not saying a word unless I can walk.
那你走吧
So walk.
什么
What?
站起来走吧
Get up off your ass and walk.
不过但愿你能在你的朋友追上你之前
But, hey, good luck getting out of the building
走出这栋大楼
before your friends catch up with you.
只要你坦白我们所要的信息
If you tell us everything we need to know,
我保证把你安排在远离加州的
I promise we will put you in a federal prison
联邦监狱
far away from California.
保证你安全
Someplace that you'll be safe.
五年前  我伤了背
Five years ago, I hurt my back.
为了帮我表兄搬张该死的沙发
I was helping my cousin move a stupid couch.
医生给我开了点儿止痛片
Doctor gave me some pain pills.
结果我欲罢不能
Turns out I liked them.
我上瘾了  自己都没觉察到
I got hooked before I even knew what was happening.
然后呢
So?
然后
So...
我在卡森泉把一个小混混
I'm chasing a gangbanger down an alley
逼到了一条巷子里  然后我的瘾上来了
in Carson Springs, and I'm out of it.
完全意识不清了
I mean, way out of it.
我以为有人跟踪我
I thought--I thought I was being followed.
我开枪打死了一个小女孩
I shot a little girl.
她十二岁
A 12-year-old girl.
当地警察采了我的血样
Local cops took my blood.
他们有目击证人  我当时死定了
They had witnesses. They had me cold.
然后来了个警探
And then this detective,
他找到我说
he reaches out to me and he says
他们可以把这事摆平
they can make it all go away.
然后真的摆平了
And they did.
血样  目击证人  都摆平了
The blood tests, the witnesses--all of it?
他们摆平那事儿以后
Hell, when they got done fixing it,
联调局还给我颁发了一枚奖章呢
the F.B.I. gave me a medal.
"他们"到底是谁
And exactly who are "they"?
我们自称为"布莱克组织"
We call ourselves the Blake Association.
为什么
Why?
"老虎  老虎"
"Tiger, tiger."
"老虎  老虎  燃烧着煌煌的火光"
"Tyger, tyger burning bright."
此处摘自郭沫若译本
来自布莱克的诗作
From the poem by Blake.
大概某人很喜欢他的作品吧
Someone's a big fan of his, I guess.
组织里还有些什么人
Well, who else is in the association?
警察  法官  联调局探员
Cops, judges, F.B.I. agents.
任何一个有秘密需要掩盖的执法人员
Anyone in law enforcement that needs a secret covered up.
比如你的毒瘾
Like your drug habit.
当你有麻烦了  向他们求助
You need a favor, you ask for it.
当他们让你做点什么  你就得照做
You get asked to do something, you do it.
"老虎  老虎"
"Tiger, tiger."
对
Yep.
组织有头目吗
Well, is there somebody who's in charge?
肯定有
Must be.
但我不知道是谁
But I don't know who.
我只知道我所接触的小团体
I just know my little group. That's it.
不过我猜测
But I'm guessing
整个组织至少有数百人  甚至上千人
there must be hundreds of us, maybe thousands.
难道就没人发觉这一切吗
And nobody knows about it?
鲍勃·柯克兰知道这事  对吧
Bob Kirkland knew about it, didn't he?
快直接招了吧  说出来给你自己一个解脱
Go ahead, just say it. Unburden yourself.
是的
Yeah.
他知道的太多了
He knew too much.
所以我杀了他
So I killed him.
你知道血腥约翰
Do you know that Red John's a member
也是布莱克组织的成员吗
of the Blake Association?
你确定吗
Are you sure?
血腥约翰有一个追随者
Red John had a follower.
丽贝卡·安德森
Rebecca Anderson.
四年前杀了几个你们的人
Killed some of your guys about four years ago.
是的  山姆·博斯科和他的小队
Yeah, Sam Bosco and his team.
就是他们
Them.
有人曾要我搞到联调局证件
Someone asked me to get F.B.I. credentials
以便他们能进入加调局
so that they could access CBI.
血腥约翰或者他的手下
Red John or someone who worked for him
潜入加调局  对丽贝卡下毒
snuck into the CBI and poisoned Rebecca.
你竟然为他们提供了帮助
And you helped them?
那时我才知道
I mean, that's when I knew.
我是在帮助一个连环杀手
I'd--I'd done a favor for a serial killer.
是谁让你搞那些证件的
Who asked you to get the credentials?
我不知道  我只是接到一通电话
I don't know. It was a phone call.
这就是组织的运作方式
That's the way the association works.
你永远不知道上线是谁
You never know.
你们
You...
你们能保证我的安全 对吧
You're gonna be able to keep me safe, right?
那要看情况了
That depends.
是你杀害了我的妻子和女儿吗
Did you murder my wife and daughter?
我没有杀你的妻子和女儿
I did not murder your wife and daughter.
以我母亲的名义起誓
I swear on my mother.
你相信他吗
Do you believe him?
他承认了谋杀罪行
He confessed to murder.
血腥约翰绝不会这么容易崩溃
Red John would never break like that,
即便是做戏也不会如此
not even as an act.
如果史密斯不是血腥约翰
Well, if Smith isn't Red John...
那就意味着我们还得继续追查
that means we have work to do.
我们需要帮助
And we need help.
谁是布伦达·夏垂克的继任者
Who took over from Brenda Shettrick?
公共关系部吗  干什么
In media relations? Why?
非常感谢大家能在临时通知后赶来
Thank you for coming on such short notice.
这位是加调局顾问派翠克·简
We have CBI consultant Patrick Jane here,
他将就血腥约翰一案的进展
who is here to report a development
进行通报
in the Red John case.
谢谢
Thank you.
十年前
Ten years ago,
被称作血腥约翰的连环杀手
the serial killer known as Red John
杀害了我的妻子和女儿
killed my wife and daughter.
自那以后  我们一直在全力追捕他
Uh, we've been hunting him diligently ever since.
今天我们很高兴地宣布
Today we're pleased to announce
我们终于确认了他的身份与面目
that we--we finally have a name, a face.
执法部门负责人
The director of the division of law enforcement,
盖尔·伯特仑局长  就是血腥约翰
Gail Bertram, is Red John.
他持有武器  极度危险
He's armed and dangerous.
如果有人发现他的行踪  切勿靠近
If you see him, do not approach him.
请立即致电加利福尼亚州调查局
Call the california Bureau of Investigation at once.
谢谢
Thank you.
请轮流提问
One question at a time.
抱歉请回避  女士
Excuse me, madam.
我们能谈谈这事吗
So are we gonna talk about this?
什么事
Talk about what?
关于伯特仑是血腥约翰的事
Bertram is Red John.
看起来就是他
Looks like.
如果让简找到他  简会杀了他的
And if Jane finds him, he's gonna kill him.
是啊
Yeah.
那我们就没问题吗  把顶头上司杀了
And we're good with that? Killing the boss?
-我无所谓  -我也是
- I am. - Yeah.
好吧
Okay.
只要我们保持步调统一
Just as long as we're on the same page.
我就是觉得有点诡异
It's just weird, is all.
伯特仑吸烟吗
Does Bertram smoke?
不吸吧
No, I don't think so.
有时候人们会收到打火机作为礼物
People get them as gifts sometimes.
范佩尔
Van Pelt.
是个闪存盘
A flash drive.
我们来瞧瞧
Let's take a look.
纳帕谷  七仙女酒厂
盘里只有一个文件
There's only one file on the drive.
有密码保护
It's password-protected.
我得硬破解
I'll have to brute-force it.
棒极了  我一直想用用我的新FPGA
Cool. I've been wanting to use my new F.P.G.A.
[FPGA: 现场可编程逻辑门排列]
你的什么
Your what?
相信我  还是别问了
Trust me, don't ask.
加州调查局  内部数据库
然后
And...
进去了
we're in.
加州调查局  内部数据库
[乱码]
该死的
Crap.
看起来像个清单
It looks like a list.
会不会是名单  你能破译吗
Names, maybe? Can you decode it?
我先试试看
I can try a few things...
但破解谜题是简的任务
But decoding is Jane's department.
我到时候发给他
I'll send it to him.
来一杯这个  这种威士忌口感很纯
Here you go. This one isn't messing around.
用了很多泥煤烘烤麦芽
Lots of peat.
很不错  能加点冰块吗
Yeah, that's pretty good. Can you put some rocks in it?
你确定吗  这可是上好的苏格兰威士忌
Are you sure? This is some fine Scotch.
我确定
Yeah, I'm sure.
那家伙跟你有点像
That guy looks like you.
连环杀人犯
即时新闻
我需要一辆车
I need a ride.
我们在去酒吧的路上了
We're en route to the bar now.
高速巡警封锁了高速公路
Highway patrol shut down the freeways,
只要他一跑我们就能抓住
so if he runs, we've got him,
但他要是躲起来怎么办
but what if he hides?
伯特仑在柑橘高地杀了个酒保
Bertram killed the bartender in Citrus Heights.
他在那边的姨妈有间房子
He's got an aunt with a house there.
你觉得他在那里吗
You think that's where he is?
她六个月之前搬到养老院去了
She moved into a retirement home about six months ago,
所以她家现在空着
so her place is empty now.
听起来是个不错的藏身之处  地址在哪
Sounds like a good place to hide. What's the address?
露丝玛丽街1408号
1408 Rosemary Street.
我们就到  让周和快速反应小组过去
We're on our way. Get Cho and R.R.T. there now,
准备好直升机
and let the choppers know.
-他在这吗  -在那里面
- Is he here? - Yes, he is. He's in there.
我让卡尔和几个人去后面了
I got Karl and a few guys in the back.
-他无处可逃  -我们能信他们吗
- He's not going anywhere. - Do we trust them?
我看了他们的肩膀  没有纹身
I asked to see their shoulders, no tattoos.
你来这里干什么  我没叫萨城警局派特警
What are you doing here? I didn't call Sac P.D S.W.A.T.
有人要我们来的
Well, someone asked for us.
在那边建一个指挥中心
Let's set up a command center right here!
听着  各位  这里由我负责
Listen, everybody, I'm in charge!
他们是从北区来的
They came from northern district.
都跨了整个城了  到底是什么情况
That's way across the town. What the hell is going on?
是他干的  他把他们叫来的
He did it. He called them in.
伯特仑把特警叫到自己这来干嘛
Well, why would Bertram call S.W.A.T. to his own location?
他不止召来了一个特警组
He didn't call in one S.W.A.T. team.
他把整个特警队都召来了
He called all of them in.
一片混乱
This is a madhouse.
屋后有整整一队别的警察在准备
There's a whole 'nother unit setting up out back.
我们无法控制局面了  头儿
We've lost control of the scene, boss.
他在他们之中  伯特仑混在他们之中
He's one of them. Bertram is one of them.
他要逃跑  我们得停止行动
He's getting away. We gotta shut it down.
谁都不许走
Nobody leaves!
一个人都不许走
No one leaves!
你安全了
You're clear.
我得吃点东西
I need something to eat.
要吃中餐么  我知道有一家很好吃
How about Chinese? I know a great place.
好  听起来不错
Yeah, sounds good.
他们在屋里发现了伯特仑的衣服
They found Bertram's clothes inside the house.
应该是有人在他去之前
Looks like someone planted a S.W.A.T. team outfit
就在房子里放好了特警服
in the house before he got there.
然后把城里所有的特警和
And then called every S.W.A.T. and
快速反应小组叫了过去
R.R.T. in the area.
知道是谁打的电话吗
Any leads about who made all those calls?
一定是个能进行大面积暗箱操纵的人
Somebody who could pull a lot of strings at once.
布莱克组织
Blake Association.
头儿
Boss.
请各位注意一下
May I have your attention, please?
放下电话  离开你们的桌子
Put down your phones and step away from your desks.
马上
Now.
我是这里特别探员主管特蕾莎·里斯本
I'm special agent in charge Teresa Lisbon.
你又是哪位
Who the hell are you?
联调局监管部门探员  丹尼斯·阿尔伯特
F.B.I. supervisory agent Dennis Abbott.
再说一遍  站起来
Now I repeat, stand up
离开桌子
and stand away from your desks...
请了
Please.
我们正在追捕
We're in the middle of a manhunt
一名极其危险的逃犯
for a dangerous fugitive.
如果你们想协助
Now if you would like to assist--
你们这个所谓的执法部门的长官
The head of this alleged law enforcement organization
是个杀人犯
is a murderer,
还是重大犯罪组织的一员
and a member of a massive criminal conspiracy.
那个组织里也有联调局探员
Which included F.B.I. agents.
对  所以局里把我
Yes, and that's why the bureau sent me here
从德州奥斯汀调过来
from the Austin, Texas, office.
收拾你们这个烂摊子
To clean up the mess.
我手里有一份
I am holding in my hand
联邦法官签署的令状
a writ from a federal judge.
联调局将立即关停你们部门
The F.B.I.'s closing down your organization right now.
所有人
All of you
解除任职
are relieved from your active duties
立即生效
as of this moment.
你不能这么做
You can't do that.
我是来收集证据的
I'm here to collect evidence.
不要妨碍我
Don't get in my way.
大伙开始吧
Let's go to work, fellas.
这是怎么了
What's going on here?
你的
That's yours.
我是联调局的丹尼斯·阿尔伯特
Dennis Abbott, F.B.I.
你一定是派翠克·简了
You must be Patrick Jane.
他们关停了我们部门
They've shut us down.
我们到时候会找你问话
We're gonna need to interview you at some point,
不过可以缓一缓  我们会在这儿待一阵子
but it can wait. We're gonna be here for some time.
别出城
Just don't leave town.
我们还有个凶手要抓
We have a killer to catch.
这案子现在归我们管了
Oh, well, that's our problem now.
你有过机会  但是搞砸了
You had your chance to catch him and you blew it--
如果你当时是真想抓他的话
if you were really trying.
这是我最喜欢的杯子
That was my favorite cup.
好  幸会  再见了
Okay, well, see you in the funny pages.
现在怎么办
What now?
不知道
I don't know.
范佩尔在伯特仑的闪存里找到了一些加密文件
Van Pelt found some coded files in Bertram's flash drive.
我们要不要从那开始查
Should we get started on those?
不用了  浪费时间而已  结束了
No, it's a waste of time. We're done.
这里没我们的事儿了
There's nothing more to do here.
回家吧  休息一下
Just go home, get some rest.
你不会放弃  我不信你会放弃
You're not quitting. I don't believe it.
不  我不是放弃
No, I'm not quitting.
是放手
I'm letting go.
目前的情况我们已经无法掌控了
It's out of our hands for now.
保持联络  好吗
But I'll be in touch. Okay?
所有的一切  我很抱歉
I'm sorry. For everything.